[Music]
hello and welcome to the junkyard love
podcast
at what age do we learn how to have
better conversations
at what age do we learn to have better
conversations with ourselves
[Music]
welcome to the junkyard love podcast it
is me your host
courage the cowardly dog i'm happy
you're here
today before we get rocking and rolling
i've got a recommendation for you in the
form
of a book i'm reading this one on
audible um i'm not even done with it yet
but it's already been so profound it's
already taught me so much it's already
just had so many
revelatory moments where i'm just saying
what
no way if you believe that a book has
the power to change your life
this is the one it's called breathe by
james nestor
breathe the new science of a lost art
check out his podcast interviews
check him out online if you want like
just a little bit of tidbits of
what you're getting into with this book
but just let me say if you suffer from
sleep apnea or any sort of breathing
problems
snoring any of these things this is your
answer
definitely check this book out breathe
by james nester n-e-s-t-o-r
i'm reading it now it's fantastic i
might just go on talking about it
multiple more times on this podcast i
think it's going to be a huge answer to
a lot of people's different problems
throughout the world so breathe james
and esther check it out today
we've got my friend abrielle dunn on the
podcast
can't wait for you guys to meet her here
we go let's get rocking and rolling
i am i am recording on my end um
we can have just kind of a soft start i
figured i can just say
welcome to the junkyard love podcast i'm
here with gabrielle dunn
that's me do you go by is is haley your
middle name i know your your model page
is abril haley
that's just because um i think abriel
dunn has a very
strong finish to a name
i don't know so i feel like gabrielle
haley sounds a little bit more
majestic abrial sounds like that's my
business name
i i actually feel that i feel like abril
haley is kind of the um
the more feminine side of yourself in a
way
yeah plus that account is sort of um you
know it's not really
it's not my personal stuff it's not i
just post
very rarely on that i've only just
recently started posting so
um you don't really get an accurate
picture of me so it's kind of who i want
you to see
and so everybody kind of sounds like
nice and relaxed and that's not really
who i
there was a am tinkle in your eye when
you said that um
yeah i isn't it interesting how
with social media it's such a strange
thing we talk about social media a lot
and just kind of it's our fa
its effects on who we are and what we do
and on society and all that
i think it's interesting because i have
a i have a separate poetry account
that is oh i follow it yeah yeah it's
it's in
my my freeness there like i feel my
my vulnerability can be even more
vulnerable and more open like
whereas my jacob from the internet
account is i try to be
as authentic as possible but there is a
little bit of boxing because there's a
brand you're trying to communicate
right even if your brand is authentic i
don't know do you ever feel a different
poll like
say you're posting to your you know to
your personal account that doesn't have
as many followers like for your friends
is to be authentic here's what i'm
really doing
and then your modeling account do you
feel different i actually
on my personal account i've actually
illuminated some followers and so i
think i'm down to like 60 people
like i i have nobody on there i it's
and it i purely feel like oh i can just
post whatever colors on my feed i want i
can post whatever
caption i want or no caption or i can
just post whatever i want
and then on my other account i
everybody and their mother that i know
sees it so
literally like my friends and their moms
follow me so
it's i my
goal in my center and i i posted it
my last post said this is my center and
it's a picture of me going like that
um that's kind of like the center of my
energy where i just feel like
everything is light and everything is
good and it's just relaxed and like
glowing i like white i like all that
kind of stuff like it's
just pure good and
that's kind of like my brand and the
message i like to portray and the energy
i like to give out and just in my
general life like i try and be
that energy and that happiness and the
positivity and just the good
good good vibes and you know everyone
obviously isn't that way but that's kind
of like my brand that's what i try and
put i was just
nice at ease let's breathe that kind of
thing i love that do you
what tell me more about your brand like
when you think of my brand or what i'm
trying to communicate
um does that does that change your
actions day-to-day is it something that
like motivates you
trying to to represent a brand and uh
it's not that i'm trying to represent a
brand
it's that i've aligned my brand with who
i feel like i
am and so my brand is
mostly my identity and
i try and keep that in all things so
like i am very authentic i'm very
vulnerable
i like to i analyze my own thoughts so
i'm happy to share my thoughts with
other people
i like to you know talk about my
struggles and how i've gone through
things how i figured them out and then
how like what the outcome was and how i
came out on top and
um i value authenticity because
it just makes you feel good and i feel
like that's just like the right type of
energy that
people should have and i feel like if
more people were authentic with their
own feelings i i know a lot of people
who
um think that they feel one a certain
way but maybe they
haven't thought about it enough and um
it's it's very like sorry i just got
distracted um
the way i feel about myself is the way i
put myself into other things and so
in everything that i do i'm like
representing that brand but it's just
who i
am i'm never gonna represent another
version of myself
i always have the same me
like there's no difference when i talk
to children
you know i don't curse but i i'm the
same i talk to them like they're a
person
i talk to them like they're an adult if
i i'm talking to
you know anyone i work with i'm the same
like i'm me when i'm talking to my
boyfriend i'm me when i'm talking to my
parents i talk to my parents just like i
would talk to anybody like i don't have
any secrets i don't hide anything
and that just like brings that like glow
about me that's what i
that's where i try and do that and so in
my work like i'm constantly trying to
be my best and be on top and i don't
give excuses because that's just
hiding and i'm always trying to just be
so authentic and then
i've started my own llc and so i do my
own video work and i talk to my own
people for that
and even in that like i put my best work
out i put my best foot forward i'm
just always trying to like i'm
passionate about your project
i'm passionate about what you're doing
you're passionate about working with me
and like this is just a passion project
that we're both doing and
like i it's the creativity that's around
and everything just makes me feel like
have you ever seen um harry potter
and the chamber of secrets of course so
when he stabs the diary and tom riddle
like explodes with light
that's what i feel like on a daily basis
i feel like i'm just like
exploding with light i'm riddle
exploding with light
yeah but i'm not dying yeah
i like that do you uh what comes to mind
is uh this term i forgot who said it but
being in right relationship with
yourself
and i feel like as a as a creator like
any
any content or any sort of branding or
any sort of
venture that you're going on when you
can be in right relationship with
yourself
you have this this circle of like self
reaffirmation of like oh this is what
i'm supposed to be doing this feels just
right this is i'm not strangling this to
get it to how i need to go
i'm just doing my thing you talked about
your brand and your llc tell me more
about
that i kind of want to i want to make
sure everybody knows all the cool stuff
you do i feel like you
have your hands my llc is kind of on the
dl
but not purposefully it's just that
um number one i don't have a lot of time
and so
i'm really just working very slowly
on it getting its legs and things like
that but
what it is is it's what i do
it's creative and digital media and
design
and production and things like that but
it's less
of what you and i do the events and it's
more of just the digital side the videos
the
um marketing material the
graphic design things like that um
and i want to specify uh that i've
learned the difference between
a graphic artist and a graphic designer
and i am a graphic designer i
can design assets i'm not great at like
making my own assets i'm not an
illustrator i'm not an artist i'm not
any kind of like that
but if you tell me like here are the
things that we have
can you put them into a design and make
it look nice yes that's my background
i've done a lot of
newspaper design layout design i've won
awards for my newspaper layout designs
i've just i've always been doing digital
design
and then as i got into video editing
that's my flow state video editing is
where
i'm like oh my god what time is it
five hours i've gone past i haven't
eaten i haven't moved i haven't done
anything wow like and my video looks
great
yeah getting into the zone yeah that's
where i
am so um with my llc
i am doing that because that's what
makes me happy those are the types of i
hope to
move from me doing the projects to
managing others doing the projects to
help me grow and get more clients and
things like that
um but right now that's what i love to
do so that's what i'm focusing on
and i've chosen my niche market to be
motivational speakers
because that's you know something that
we are both familiar with
and something that so the llc is
called elevate media and it's spelled
e-l-o-e like my name elevate
um i added two l's and some people think
it's wrong but it's not wrong
i like it i like it thank you um so
the point of it i want to elevate
designs and it's a little cliche with
i've looked up a lot of
companies called elevate and it's all
the same thing like we're trying to lift
we're trying to elevate we're trying to
whatever you're doing we're going to
make it
that much better whatever so i'm on that
train of
i want to elevate everything in there
you're doing but
i think it aligns with my my personal
goal
in life to just which i don't know yet
obviously i don't know my full potential
but i just feel like i'm supposed to
spread all of this energy like i feel
like i'm just
full of it and exploding with it and i
want people to have it there's just
it has come from when i was younger that
i'm
was always that person that you could
come to and i would just send you novels
of advice and how to help you and i'm
here for you and
all of these kinds of things and i was
always that person and i still am that
person and
i just i i'm the type of person like
when anyone needs help
i will drive however many hours to go
help them if they need it
like i'm just like i'll drop everything
and go like i just want to help i just
want to spread good stuff and so
i found that a way to spread
there are people who are putting out
good messages but they're not being
heard
because they either don't have good
enough videos they're not making videos
they're not putting themselves out there
whatever
and so i want to help people who are
putting positive messages out
get their messages heard and so that's
kind of where i am
i've been working with someone who
he works in like business strategy and
he just had an event called the uprising
and so he had elevate media produce his
uprising videos
and so that was pretty cool and we had a
great relationship so i'm building that
relationship there
um and it's just been it's been really
fun to
build my own llc and figure out what i
want to do with it but it's also
you know it's kind of scary but i don't
want to get into the
i don't want to paralyze myself by how
many options there are
and how many people i'm sure are doing
the same things that i'm doing
right because there are so many
opportunities and i think there's enough
for everybody
and i'm a huge proponent of failing
forward
so if i continue to invest my time and
nothing happens or nothing comes of it
or
um you know i make it i make a business
relationship and it turns out poorly or
you know anything happens like i'm going
to learn from that experience and keep
moving forward and
everything i've been doing with the
company so far has been
awesome so i'm just happy to do that and
i'm happy to see it grow and i'm happy
to
hopefully get more people who you know
are into the motivational speaking that
need video services you know the guy
that i ended up with
um he was just thinking
he was telling me he was just thinking
about how he didn't have anybody to
produce videos for him and he wanted to
do video projects and i was in his inbox
that day being like hey do you need any
video projects
so i'm putting myself out there i'm just
contacting random motivational speakers
on youtube that
i'm you know like doing cold emails but
it's me personally emailing being like
hey i saw your stuff i really like the
message you're putting out and i work
with you
so yeah i love that that's actually cool
to hear i feel like we've
we've briefly touched on this but i
didn't know is this in in
depth i'm super excited for you that's
awesome do you find
because so so the work we do we both um
we've worked together on a lot of
student organizations where there is a
lot of motivational speakers keynote
speakers
um so we've both seen quite a few
um it's something it's it's part of the
job that for me
um especially when we're working live
for audio for
so so when i'm working audio that's the
time when i get to like all right well
he's talking i'm good so i get to absorb
it and i i
i value that honestly in in my job like
i really enjoy
listening to motivational speakers um i
do awesome
yeah like so so we've seen a a lot over
the years what it
when you think of motivational speakers
or when you
even the feeling that you feel that you
are trying to like now that you have you
have a company going forward you're like
the feeling that i've
felt within me when i hear motivational
speakers i want to
i wish that on other people uh what what
is that feeling
too because i'm always trying to pick up
a couple extra people like people who
are like well the motivational tony
robbins thing isn't really my style
but i think that everybody values from
these
um just corners of of human
communication and speech especially when
someone's up on a stage and they're
telling you their
authentic story here's how i conquered
this part of my life here's how
i deal with these parts of my human
emotions and here's how you can too
i think that when people receive
something they can receive it as many
times as they do in their life but it
takes that
one time that they receive it correctly
that it really
resonates with them and so
i think what you're mentioning about the
tony robbins thing i also
i feel that like i'm not a fan of tony
robbins but i'm a fan of motivational
speakers and people who speak like him
i'm just he just doesn't do it for me
you know what i mean
and so i think it's important
for people to be exposed to higher
levels of thinking
people who were lower and have gotten
higher because of whatever they've gone
through and whatever
things they've overcome because i think
a lot of people
don't think that it's possible to
overcome something or they don't even
it's not that they don't think it's
possible they just don't it's not in
their realm of thinking
at all and so like i know people who
um i won't name any names but uh someone
that's really close to me
or close to me um she just kind of
lives her life and works a minimum wage
job and
doesn't really care and her boyfriend's
a minimum wage job too
and they live in like a nice apartment
that's
you know whatever but they're they just
that's it like they are fine with that
and she works at like plato's closet or
something and it's just
that's what she's just gonna do and i
don't
i want more for her and i want her to
see that there is more out there
and i feel like some people just their
life
is so their life that they just can't
imagine anything outside of it
and my message every day to anyone i
talk to
is that you can wake up every day and do
it differently
and like you can wake up and quit your
job if you want to you can quit your job
and then find a new one like you can
quit your job lose your apartment and
you have a completely different life
i've had in my life i've moved out of an
apartment
in one day and i had nowhere to go and i
was
i put stuff into storage units and i was
sleeping on friends couches and
um then i moved into a friend's room and
then i moved into a house i found on
craigslist and then
i moved back into a friend's room and
then i lived at home and then i
um finally found an apartment and it was
just you know it's crazy but that's what
i made my life because i was
uncomfortable with
what it was and i feel like people are
so comfortable
in what they're doing that they don't
reach for more
and i feel like listening to
motivational speakers or just
having access to them and knowing they
exist and hearing their messages that's
just so important and that's what
that's why i'm always that's what i'm
always trying to get people to do
and so your question of what do i want
people to feel
inspired like i want i want them to feel
inspired i want them to know that
there's more i want them to know that
their way of doing things is not the
only way there's
there are so many things in life that
you've been taught that aren't the only
way to do things you know like
um my mom when she cooks she always cuts
the fat off meat
and i started cooking and keeping or the
fat in the skin
i started cooking and keeping the skin
on me and i'm like this is delicious why
would you do anything differently
like so just there are just little
things everywhere in every aspect of
your life that can be done differently
that you've been taught
are the way to do things and then you do
them differently and you're like this is
so much better why wouldn't i
have done that before right yeah
do you do you do you feel that because i
share some of those sentiments i
i'm always um i i guess i haven't always
been this way
but i do i think naturally try to
see the good in people to put it simply
like it's um
like like we you know talking about you
know your friends you're mentioning
it's like it's not that you know their
life is terrible or they're messing it
up or anything it's just like
dude i know you and i know you're
amazing so i want you to tap into that
like
because for me it's a lot of this hey
don't you remember we're gonna die one
day like you should really try to live a
self-actualized life
um i think a lot a lot of people like us
see we just see the best in people
or or we the the parts that we do
connect with in people that are that we
love about them
we want the rest of the world to meet
them on that level
and so when you kind of kind of wake up
every day
or um just just add that momentum to
your life
of what can i do today that's that's
incredible like how can i feed the good
wolf in me rather than the wolf who just
wants to be comfortable like because
today what i can do i can wake up and i
can um
just do the bare minimum like the i okay
my bills are paid
my you know i didn't fight with my
neighbor
i i you know i took care of my business
but um i didn't go the extra mile i
didn't push myself i didn't think about
my future i didn't think about
what could i do for 10 minutes a day for
the next 10 years that will add up to
something incredible that i'm going to
be very proud of
yeah and i yeah i think tapping into
that and just seeing that in people
shines through i i feel like and you
definitely have an ability to do it
because we've been friends for a while
um and i feel like we'll get into these
long text streams
where i feel more confident in myself
afterwards
we'll kind of empower each other you
know i always like to say easily
inspired
i love to be inspired and sometimes
we're we're easily down on ourselves
especially as creatives we're always
comparing ourselves
we're talking about social media
sometimes we feel a little confined by
our brand or what we want to do
but uh when someone can can believe in
you or insert that inspiration into your
life it's kind of like
cool yeah i'm going to lean more into
that so yeah i
i feel like you would be good
i mean just as like a manager spot you
know
creative director you're
you're good at understanding people
where they're at
and and you can connect with that
version of them really well you've
always been really good at that where
did you
go go ahead i think i'm very emotionally
intelligent
about myself i spend a lot of time
studying myself
analyzing my thoughts why did i think
about thinking that thought
you know i just i get very into it and
so
i understand where i'm coming from and i
understand my creative struggles and so
it's
i also um when i was in school i studied
video games
and i was the producer and to be the
producer
just to major in video games you have to
enter into every single
part every role so i've done coding i've
done
illustration i've done the um
what is it game design level design
um i've done ui design i've done
you know the story design coming up with
the narrative just i've done every role
in video games and so as once i got to
the producer status
doing all the documentation and managing
my team
and i managed a big team of 16 to i
think
at most i had like 20-ish people um
i had to understand what they were going
through and if i was assigning them
deadlines
what i was asking of them like i if i
was to say
i need you to have this feature done
tomorrow i need to know that i'm asking
them to do
48 hours of work in 24 hours
and so i'm very conscious of that in my
job and the work that we do
like i'm a creative person i know i kind
of i try to wrap
my head around what everyone is doing
and so whether it's lighting design and
i know someone needs to sit down and
plug in their console and figure out how
the lights are going to do their thing
and go through the script and find those
moments and then
pick the colors and then show them to
the producer and then have to fix them
and then have to go back and go through
the script and fix all the parts that
had to be fixed or whatever
i know that those things take time so
when i'm asking someone to do something
and they're frustrated i have to think
you know what have i asked them to do
and i have to be understanding because i
feel like that's
that sort of pressure is um i think
comes from an
old way of thinking in an old way of
managing and
i i don't think asking the impossible of
people is
nice and whether or not it's nice you
know like it gets the job done but i
also
you know it's important that you keep
people and you
can you can keep people by
treating them nicely like you know if i
were to just
make sure everyone was doing their jobs
happily like that doesn't even
necessarily keep people
it's making sure that they feel valued
and so
that's why i'm constantly like whether
you're doing your job
or not like i want to know why what
makes you so good or why are you
struggling
and if you know there are people who um
haven't met deadlines like what's going
on and why
and you know then i find out they just
got out of the hospital and i'm like
okay and they're like no but i'll have
it to you tonight and i'm like damn this
person is a trooper
you know and so i just i
my energy flows into my work
and so when i connect with another
person i feel like i connect with their
energy
and i i have to understand them like
my only way for understanding people is
trying to learn
i have to become emotionally intelligent
about them
and so in all my relationships and
and every person that i know i know i
can go to people for certain things
because
i become emotionally intelligent about
who they are and how they'll react to
certain situations
and so i try and test the waters a
little bit sometimes where i'll text
something that maybe
i wouldn't have texted them before or
i'll say something that i wouldn't have
said before
and i'll see how they react and if they
don't react well then that's just not
something i talk to talk about that
with that person but you know sometimes
i react really well and i'm like okay
you're a great source for this type of
thing and so like i know i can go to you
for specific things and
you'll always come back with good
feedback and good thoughts and good
advice and things like that so
um that's kind of how
i learned to be that way but that just
comes naturally
my name abrielle means mother of all
things
oh does it i didn't know that yeah
that's awesome that's like the coolest
that's that's the best name ever then
yeah so
like i said i feel like i'm exploding
with energy like i feel like my energy
is everywhere and i am in everything and
i
it just when i am talking to people i'm
experiencing them and i'm trying to i'm
working on being more present
and so i had a problem with it when i
was
you know just getting out of college and
i was like i have a job
i'm in school i got this to do i got
this to do like yeah give me a second i
just have to do this thing and hold on
give me a second and
okay i'm with you but i gotta rush and i
gotta do this thing and i'm working on
compartmentalizing
and not necessarily slowing down but
you know like i'm with you today from
this time to this time
and between that window i'm all with you
like there's my house yeah and like i
know i have other things to do and i
know
um before i was with you i was doing
something else but
all of the things surrounding that and
everything in my day
is just compartmentalized like i'm
here so the the importance of fighting
you know things like distraction it
comes up so
when you because this is something that
i used to struggle with too
is um you know like i would identify
someone with adhd and so it's like as
i'm talking with someone i'm just like
pay attention pay attention keep
listening okay what'd they just say
think about that no no don't think about
that
like you're just coaching yourself
through this being present but
for me it's something that i've learned
you know certainly with meditation and
practice and the podcast and just
all these different things that i've
done um now
i'm good at being present i'm good at
being here
and tentative and i'm not thinking of um
all these other things so
there it almost becomes a skill of yes i
know that i have these other things
going on
but i'm here so i'm going to turn those
off because thinking about those
while i'm trying to do this is not
helpful actually i can't fully be here
and
i think that being being present with
someone there's something about you know
even through
even through video even through text
even through phone calls there's
something that we can intuitively feel
like okay this person is here listening
to me this person is
is sharing this this space with me
they're they're really
um listening to that that part within
myself that i want
to be listened to it's connections that
human connection that we are
built off of biologically you know i i
feel like even through a screen it
doesn't matter like i
i lose sight of it being through a
screen i feel like i'm talking to you it
doesn't
it doesn't feel weird it doesn't feel
whatever and i i also feel that in
on the phone you know i don't live with
my family my brother lives in
gainesville my parents live in west palm
beach and
um i call my parents and then we phoned
in my brother and then
i put my phone down and i start making
breakfast and we're all just hanging out
in the kitchen together
you know like it's i don't i don't see
the barrier of technology i'm happy to
have it but
um you know like it facilitates so much
it's obviously
detrimental in some ways which we've
talked about but i
i love it and so i don't it's that human
connection that's important and that's
why
you know i watch so many podcasts and
things like that i just want
human connection and i just i love
learning and
growing myself and finding new ways to
build and spread my energy
and listening to other people talk helps
me do that
and hearing other people and talking to
other people just satisfies that
connection
so 100 100 do you think that
i i feel like the ability to do that and
just kind of what
um not just social media but our ability
to connect in different ways
like this is i mean it's still pretty
new just as humanity
of like what we're able to do uh we talk
a lot about kind of like the future and
um you know what technology has effects
on us and that sort of thing that's
always super fun to get into with you um
do you think that like right now
i mean there's a lot we're losing out on
in the world you know i think of
kids in school and stuff and they're
i mean they're adjusting to this whole
new thing and there's a lot of
charisma and interaction with other
humans that like they're
they're probably getting worse at you
know like we're more in our homes but
there is this there is this you know i
think of
i just had um trevor may on last week
and just the the fluidity of his kind of
conscious thought because he's a game
streamer
like he's just being himself he's just
with himself and he's and he's you know
there's young kids there's
there's older guys who are just laughing
along enjoying his company just this
stream of thought and he's not really
self-policing himself he's not
trying to present himself in any way
it's this this openness
i i don't know what what do you think
about the
i guess the future uh of of us as humans
as if we continue down this road because
i feel like when we're more open to each
other when we're more susceptible to
looking for what's true
in in one another and allowing each
other the space to
just feel out what we're going through
and just have kind of
this fluid stream of consciousness this
this
mindsync is what i what i said a couple
days ago
yeah so i think it it varies and so what
you mentioned about
kids in school they're definitely going
to be different
because i think this stuff is great but
nothing beats being in person because
even in nature you literally give off
pheromones and chemicals and
like you are emitting things and whether
there are some people who want to talk
about energy is not real
and i get that and i'm not i'm not a
huge energy buff i don't want to be like
i feel your core near my core like i'm
not like that
i'm not there but no offense to anyone
that is there but
my core is offended i just
like i i feel people
and so when you're with someone you can
feel them
if you say something wrong you can feel
tension it does it's not necessarily
eliminated
in these types of um formats
even when you're on the phone you know
like you can say something wrong and
then
you hear silence and they're like what
do you mean
and like you can feel like oh i didn't
i'm sorry i didn't mean to say it like
that or
you can you can feel that there's
tension but when you're with someone
even like they're they're in the way
their entire body moves like you
literally it's electricity you just feel
it it's in the air
you feel differently and so i think
that if we continue down this path of
only being
online and things like that not good for
us it's just
we don't get that electricity
and then in the sense of kids in school
i actually took on a babysitting job um
babysitting kids who were doing online
school
and so i got to see what they were doing
and see
and it was really cool i got to look at
a second grader and a fourth grader
and so what the fourth grader was having
to do was kind of more
normal school stuff like they're they've
already been in school so they
understand like okay you have math
homework do your math homework and then
the difference was like you have to take
a picture of your math homework and then
send the picture and so they would teach
you how to do those kinds of things
the second grader was learning how to
use his computer
and so in order to like they would
decorate their notebook
in class they the teacher gave them a
powerpoint and it was a blank slide with
a
like a blank notebook a picture of a
notebook on it and then the other slides
had
stickers that you would copy and paste
to put on the blank notebook
and it taught them to use copy and paste
in powerpoint
and move things around and scale and
flip and
insert an image and search to find an
image and it was a very
interesting way to teach a kid how to
use a computer
and he thought he was just designing a
notebook
and so i i think like those things are
very cool
but also you know like he's in this
meeting with all of his
classmates and he's got his headphones
on and he's just like
sitting there like this and i'm like
what are you doing he's like all the
teachers talking
i'm like yeah you're supposed to be
paying attention he's like oh
she can't see me
so it just you know it's you know you'd
be in class and you start to put your
head down and your teacher's like
no yeah i would always be pulling out my
tech decks and
fingerboarding and they'd always try to
take those away it's funny because as i
get older
if i'm genuinely interested in the
subject and it's something that i've
committed to listening and wanting to
learn
um this is just in line with kind of
learning how you learn i suppose and
we're all kind of adjusting especially
young people right now adjusting to
different ways of learning
um now as an adult i can i'll tech deck
and i'll put headphones on something i'm
interested in
and it would be kind of like my my leg
twitch like i'll be playing with this
as i'm maybe i'll pick up a pen and
paper and take some notes but i feel
like i'm actually listening
because this is a mindless mindless
little thing i can be doing a little
leg twitch um but yeah it's kind of like
the fidget spinners i feel like we all
have
especially in the age of technology
there's some form of you know adhd
attention span um not not
problems but changes you know our
ability to
pay attention and pay attention to more
things is
increasing and decreasing in you know
maybe not so great ways so we're all
adjusting to that i like what you said
about that
people learn how they learn um
i definitely think that's a thing that
kids need to learn
and i experience that in watching all
this virtual schooling
is you know the teacher would say like
you need to study your flash cards and
the kids like i hate flash cards and why
do i have to do flash cards and it's
like
it's not that you have to do flashcards
it's that they're teaching you
a way to study you don't have to study
that way it might just be better for you
to
if you're a photographic memory you just
look at the page and you're good
it might be better for you to write them
down on page and rewrite and rewrite
rewrite into repetition it might be
better for you to say them out loud
or it might be better for you to have a
flash card and
go through it so i think it's important
to learn how you learn
but also the
virtual learning and the virtual aspect
of all this stuff like
nothing beats i i know that with
business meetings and stuff
nothing beats getting together with your
team
and you know like hashing something out
in person
the zoom is great and it's
much better than like being on the phone
or just doing it through email
for sure but it's just
so different in person you know like
it's just not something that we even
and i don't necessarily know what it is
but you know what i feel like on a zoom
meeting when i'm in a zoom meeting
for hours like i feel like i can't go to
the bathroom or
i can't eat or take a drink of water or
something like that so
if i'm in work meetings for two hours
i'm sitting there like focused and it
is exhausting you know what i mean yeah
yeah
you know the the inhuman aspect is
is underrated like we can efficiently do
more
with with zoom calls with you know um
technology communication there but there
is i mean
just down you know when when you think
of a um a handshake like you make a deal
you say some big corporation shirt and
tie type guy
you make a deal you shake hands that
exchanges the chemical oxytocin back and
forth between two humans which is kind
of the feeling of trust within us
um i mean we're missing in you know you
mentioned pheromones too think about all
the things that
we're not even totally in tune with or
maybe is
you know other people have proof but you
and i just don't really understand it
fully there's
there's a lot of aspects of you know
where
we're trying to communicate feeling and
meaning by words and in communication
and talking but there's all these
underlying factors of
us as biological creatures that feel
differently when we're in the presence
of one another our
our team um that we work with for for
live event production for example like i
feel like we all vibe really well off
each other
you know we're we're we're pretty close
close crew we
um like like when we're doing a live
show
you know when i'm jamming i'm in the
zone and i look over in
in the lighting guy or tyler or whoever
is is just
right there with me like there's you
could there's just this communication
it's kind of like being in a band
jamming on stage where
you don't exactly have it all 100
rehearsed you know there's a couple
things that are going to happen on the
fly it's this
this communication this jazz riff i'm
going to do this and you do this
we got it like it's it's a head nod so
it's it's uh you know humans are
incredible it's cool that we're
adjusting to all this stuff
um i can't wait to get back to
to kind of um i won't say normal but
whatever
our our next stage of
um modes of being
bounce back i think just based on like
what we've gone through in history and
where we ended up just a few years ago
and now where we are now like i think
it's in cycles and i think we'll be fine
i think everything is going to be fine
but i like what you were saying about
our team and that we vibe
i i what i like about that is we're able
to communicate without actually speaking
and we just get each other and
everyone's kind of on the same page
especially during a show and so
if someone you know flubs something we
like look over at each other and we know
we did it and we're like yeah you did
that
but you know it's all good and we all
laugh it off and we we do the show or
someone's supposed to do something and
they don't so someone makes up for it
and the show keeps going and like
everyone gets it
yeah okay so so i want to just because
it keeps popping into my mind um
i want to just skip back a little bit to
motivational speakers
who's your who's your juice like who's
your bread and butter because
you know if you're going to be the the
talent coordinator do you have anybody
that stands out or do you just
like motivational speakers is there
something you listen to often or
yeah i don't have anyone that stands out
and i wouldn't say i listen to
motivational speakers
often um i listen to joe rogan but i
don't know
him as a motivational speaker like he
kind of counts sometimes he gets on
these rants and i'm like
speaking my brother
uh there are definitely but also in my
research for
the company that i have i just um
i do i've started following more
motivational accounts and i've started
you know like i don't want to work with
someone that
i don't believe in my
what i count as a huge blessing is that
i
have a job i have an income stream and
i'm not worried about it
so when i'm starting this company i can
make it exactly what i want
i don't have to i'm not scrounging for
clients
i'm not scrounging for money so i can go
after the people i really believe in
and so i'll watch a motivational speaker
and i'm like this person really isn't
interesting to me so i don't reach out
to them but
if i am inspired by someone i'm like i
really love your message and i want more
people to hear it and i want to
give you a medium and help you facili i
want to facilitate
you reaching people well i don't have
anyone specifically but i just
i enjoy reading quotes i
enjoy you know little motivational clips
i enjoy
anything that and i enjoy these types of
conversations i would count
a ton of my friends as motivational
speakers you know like
just because they don't have that title
doesn't mean that when i talk to them
i'm not motivated you know what i mean
so there are tons of situations where
i'm feeling down on myself i reached out
to you recently where i was
feeling down on myself and also that
problem
wasn't you know it wasn't like this
specific thing was wrong and that's what
i needed to fix
it was kind of an overarching thing that
i needed to address in multiple avenues
and so i went to you for one aspect of
it i went to
a personal trainer i worked with for
another aspect of it i went to my family
for another aspect of it i went to my
boyfriend for another aspect
and through all of those different roads
i was able to reach the solution and
feel better
and i'm able to mirror you know like
talking about things is so helpful
and i talk to myself a lot and i figure
things out but
i don't necessarily have other people's
experiences and
that's what i'm seeking is how people
have navigated themselves
right yeah i love that i love i mean
just just the ability to say
man i got this thing i'm going through
and i sure as heck don't have all the
answers for it so like let's see what my
wonderful friends have to say about it i
love that
you know i i feel like i have my own
versions of doing that i
um in the the description for the
podcast is mining the hearts of one
another
um and i think that that's that's been a
huge thing for me
um is there wasn't a lot in my life
that i was taught like like it's all
just kind of like figured out on your
own and so me
i'm observing everybody i'm with like my
my friends
the parents of my friends i'm like how
would they react to this situation
what's you know even if it's not just
going directly to them for advice
i feel like when you can kind of learn
by observation and learn by different
people's perspectives
and then you could take it in you don't
have to listen to it right away you
don't have to say like yes that's true
but you can say like
huh what do i think about that and like
how does their perspective
change mine in this moment and explore
that a little bit more i think that's a
that's a very helpful mindset to have
that you have that you're able to just
take in these these different um
different ways of observing the same
observing the same problem you know it's
also different
in different cultures and i think that's
important to think about too
you know like as much as i haven't i've
traveled a little bit i've been to
you know a few other countries but it's
not like i've traveled the world
but in the in learning about other
cultures and in the traveling that i
have done
and meeting new people like people
are the way they are because of the way
they've been raised and
you know nature and nurture but also
just because of the culture that they're
rooted into
and so there are some people that it's
taken me forever to understand who they
are and as i learn about the culture
that they've come from
then i begin to understand who they are
so
there's also you know some cultures
value
different things differently and so
there are some problems that
white americans have that in other
countries
just don't exist you know like they
don't think about it as
hard or it's not a problem that comes up
because someone else is dealing with it
or
you know like if there's any type of you
know if you think about loneliness
if you are feeling lonely and you
haven't been around a lot of people and
all that kind of stuff and then you look
at spanish families who
just constantly have like all of their
meals are together they have big meals
at all their um holidays everyone gets
together
spanish families are huge everyone loves
each other they're just
it's a huge big family it's hard to feel
lonely in the spanish family i won't
speak for anyone that's spanish and
you know like is lonely i'm sure that's
a thing that comes up
but it's just something to think about
that i'm always taking into
consideration
when i feel one certain way like why why
am i feeling this way
who else could be feeling this way where
does it come from how is it related to
the culture that i'm in
how is it related is it related to any
societal pressures that i'm feeling
why am i feeling those societal
pressures like the the thing that i was
um
coming to you recently was i was just
not feeling good about myself or about
my gym performance and just
my work performance like i was just
overall not feeling like i was my best
or i was doing my best or
not even that i wasn't doing my best i
just felt like what i was doing wasn't
good and i had to go ahead
what were the conclusions that you came
to with that well i had to sit back and
say
good compared to what and i had to
realize that i was comparing myself
even to things i know i shouldn't
compare myself to and
um one of the things i've done on social
media recently to
you know like help my device usage is
i've turned off all my notifications and
i've stopped following like super pretty
people
and or i've muted accounts or i i don't
um i don't follow them anymore like
traveling accounts and
just models and fitness people people i
don't know that i just look at their
profiles or their pictures
because they're nice to look at like
travel
photos like places i've never been to
that i you know
desired to go to it's really just a
waste of time just scrolling through
those things and i'm comparing my life
to these
girls or women or groups of people
or activities or places i want to go why
can't i go these places why haven't i
been there why doesn't my body look like
that why am i not
you know that successful why am i not
doing this it's just useless
i'm the best i can be in where i am
right now
and i have plans to be more and i'm on
the path of being more and i know my own
ambition and i kick myself in the ass
every day like
i don't i don't feel like i'm actually
struggling
i only feel that way when i'm looking at
other people
and so that whole issue was i just found
that i was just comparing myself
and why you know i should only be
comparing myself to myself
who i was yesterday or who i was when i
wasn't doing as well
and who i was when i wasn't doing as
well was not as good as who i am today
so i think i'm doing pretty good yeah
yeah no i love all that i really like
your perspective on that when was your
first time when you first got social
media how old were you and like what was
your experience with it because i'm
always trying to
um devise kind of you know how
has social media changed us and and for
me um i graduated high school 2010
and iphone came out 2008 or 2007.
i say this a lot i should remember that
but um
i i i just really always observe like
man i wonder who i would be if we never
had social media
if i was never really super into social
media who would i be how would i
um compare myself to other people
differently
um so as it's something that we're
learning to as we become older
adults we kind of learn these wise ways
of dealing with it you're like oh
looking at these this is it's cool that
i get to see these fit people
it's cool that i get to see these
beautiful places but that's just kind of
a nice picture it does actually give me
this feeling of man i wish i was doing
that so you you being able to
recognize the you know intuitively feel
the
the feelings and emotions that these
things on our feed
stir within us then you're able to kind
of flip the switch and be like i'm going
to make this my
you know my daily motivational board
right
so you're the beginning of social media
for you and kind of like how you've
adapted to it now to make it to your
benefit so i think i started
i definitely started social media on
myspace and i think that was
uh like eighth grade i wanna say i got a
cell phone when i was
13. maybe 12. i know my parents said i
was gonna have to wait until i was 13
but they may have given it to me when i
was 12
which i don't agree with probably pretty
that's probably pretty early for back
then
yeah well i mean yes and no i'm
there's six-year-olds getting phones now
and so i know
now but it's so weird is that i mean
that's just the new normal though
this yeah it really is but yeah so i
started on i mean i first had
aim i don't know if that counts as
social media but um
i was on that i went from aim to
runescape which i don't it's not really
um social media either but
i was on there talking um to myspace and
then myspace
had its own like you could put where
your
your top eight friends or whatever and
then there was like the
bulletin board where you could do those
fun surveys and
enter your own stuff and then forward
them to other people and everyone else
would do your bulletin board surveys
um and then there were a few email
surveys that i feel like
also happened that were similar to that
myspace thing
yeah and then um i went to
facebook and i had facebook until the
end of high
school and i deleted my facebook after
high school
i never i had twitter i had tumblr
um but tumblr was very i didn't share
who i was
until like my later later years of
tumblr
and then i was just posting like
it was just kind of my outlet but also i
posted like pretty pictures
or whatever go ahead
well it's just interesting i'm wondering
if you notice um looking back now like
are these different facets of yourself
like are these different
kind of sides of your personality that
are amplified when they're on certain
platforms um i don't know but i know
that it's easy
to be someone else when there isn't a
face attached to it a face or a name
so i know that specifically for tumblr i
never had
like i always had my profile photos like
a silhouette of me
and then i just posted whatever pictures
i never really posted any blogs or
anything personal and so i just kind of
had a
nice account with a decent amount of
followers because i was just reposting
other people's pretty pictures
tumblr's about that mysterious vibe to
it yeah
but then once i got instagram i was
against having instagram and then i got
instagram in high school
and i was like i just don't want to post
my stuff like it doesn't make any sense
that you would do that
and here i am posting all my stuff
um but now you do modeling on instagram
yeah
and so what i think what i've
realized the difference in social media
now
versus what it was when i was younger is
that you would log on
and like see all of your friends that
you know and see what they're doing and
see what they're up to and this person
checked in here or
you would check the myspace bulletin
board and see what they answered to all
those like what's your favorite color
and all that kind of stuff like you
would learn about
your circle and then you could design
your whole myspace page and
it would be who you are and you would go
on other people's pages and be like oh i
want my cursor to look like that and
learn how to code that cursor and stuff
like that
so that was a cool past time where you
were actually learning about the people
that you know
and now i feel like the past time that
we have is
mindlessly scrolling through pretty
pictures that
entertain our brain that aren't really
teaching us and even if they are
teaching us like even if they are a
bulletin board of positive thoughts
like what are they actually doing i'm
actually getting a little bit sick of
the positivity like i feel like there
was a lot of negativity
and so like if you just one really small
portion of it like fat shaming
people who are overweight felt bad about
themselves and there was a lot of
negativity towards them and all that
kind of stuff
and so then there's been this swing to
the opposite side
where you love your body love your shape
all the stores are coming out with like
all the shapes and sizes of clothing and
like it's really great
but there's just so much like love
yourself love yourself love yourself be
who you want to be
do this you can do whatever you want you
can do it i feel like there's
so much self-help that it's just
sickening like it's
it's almost so toxic like you're allowed
to hate yourself
sometimes like you shouldn't make a
mistake and just love yourself like you
need to learn from it and
feel bad about it and you shouldn't have
done that you shouldn't have
whatever you know and so i just i feel
like there's
so much be successful be this
be that and that's what instagram is is
everything is happy and
everything is that brand of being
wonderful
and it's just it's ju it's so much like
i feel like everyone is just trying to
be
so happy and i even see it and people
that i know and i know the struggles
that they go through and then i look at
their instagram and it's like
amazing everything is great and i'm just
like
what like it it's such a great
um case study i guess to look at that
because like i know
what you're going through is hard and
you're just posting that
everything's great and it's easy like
that is such
a specific example that is just like
everything on instagram like
there are women who post it whatever and
they are their body looks great but if
you really like
if you're a girl and you know how to
post like you know that they're standing
a certain way
in a certain lighting they've added a
certain filter they've edited a certain
way like
you know that that photo was the best of
160 photos that they took and that one
just happened to like contour their butt
properly
and they just look a great they look
like they have a big butt and a skinny
stomach but like
when they moved one angle difference
like they
it showed the pancakes that they ate
that morning like it's just not
and so i feel like that is what i have
tried to eliminate in all of my watching
the social dilemma and learning about
i've started following tristan's harris
movement of the the humane technology
whatever the movement is
signed up for it and get all the
suggestions about how to use your device
less and how to use it more consciously
and things like that so
i've turned my notifications off i told
you i followed those pretty people that
just make me mindlessly scroll i've just
recently put my phone on grayscale mode
so it's not pretty to look at and i'm
not
distracted by all the nice colors that
are rewarding to my brain
have you noticed a difference from that
yet like yeah is it kind of like this
thing where you're not pulled in by all
these fantastic colors
it is i noticed myself i still do go on
instagram but also on instagram i have a
timer so on my personal account i have
15 minutes a day and on my
other account i have 30 minutes a day
and when they go off i'm done and so
yeah i spend 45 minutes a day at most on
instagram and sometimes
on my personal account i don't even get
the notification
until like night time that i've spent my
15 minutes for the day
yeah well yeah i don't use them and
the thing with the grayscale is that um
i've designed my background to be really
nice and it's really colorful and it's
all these pictures from my trip to
mexico
and it's beautiful and when it's on
grayscale like
it doesn't hit the same way you know and
so
when i look at my phone like oh what
pretty pictures i want to look at more
pretty pictures and so i open my phone
and start scrolling through instagram or
start scrolling through my camera roll
and
if they're just black and white photos
are really cool and dramatic but they're
just not as cool as what i know they are
and so i've set up um
shortcuts on my phone to change it from
grayscale to color
so that if anyone's like do you like
this shirt or i need this color or
whatever like i can quickly
change it but i've kept it on grayscale
for most of the day
and if i do end up changing it because i
need to see something
and i and i leave it just out of habit
i notice that i'm more um
taken into it i'm on it more i'm get
back into that habit of just getting on
instagram and scrolling through it and
i'm like no this is what we don't want
to do
back on grayscale and get off yeah i
think i think that
setting limits and kind of exploring
what works for all of us as individuals
when it comes to social media and our
social media use is
it's it's right now it's huge you know
but i think it's going to be something
that we're going to look back and like
oh a lot of humans had to kind of like
relearn the act of social media so for
me
um i remember i had quit i had quit
social media
i mean probably two years ago or so um i
quit for almost a year i got off of it
and i was just really on my
my self-development kick i was just
really like trying to find myself i went
through um
i started learning like um this is what
i would consider i kind of had like a
spiritual awakening and it's kind of an
intense
phrase but um just learning all these
things about myself and
learning why am i doing this and what's
my behavior trying to get from here and
um what what's what validation am i
seeking from
from this and um i remember i had we
went to this breakfast place in portland
and i had been on social media for a
while and and it was just so great to
hang out friends i was in a great mood
and uh there was this i i got a coffee
and it was this very
like hipster bottle it's portland like
right right downtown
or right around hawthorne and uh i was
just transfixed by this bottle basically
this this thing that i got my coffee and
it was just like this little stout
cool shape cool color cool design and i
remember being
like i was noticing how much i loved
this thing
and i was like man this is like it's
just a bottle man it's it's not that big
of a deal but i was
in the moment i was like this is awesome
i really am enjoying this bottle
what a great design i was going on about
it was like i took a molly right before
i walked in there or something
um but it's but what it was was
you know we're so used to not only being
sold to
but just having things be so perfect all
the time as you're scrolling through
it's like
wow there's a beautiful waterfall but
you can make it look even more
vibrant and beautiful by adding all
these filters and effects so
does that dull the senses when we do see
an actual waterfall and it's kind of a
an overcast day is it not as pretty to
us does it not strike us as much so
just noticing the without even trying by
removing social media and removing a lot
of this like
want for perfection and better and more
and all this stuff it makes its value
our everyday interactions a little bit
more like
i'm pumped that i was able to see this
little uh glass bottle of coffee
and just be transfixed by it honestly i
thought that was a cool thing
but i think that also comes from you
being a creative and you knowing that
with anything that is made there's a
whole process behind
it and who
who designed that bottle why is it that
shape why is it glass why isn't it this
why isn't it that why is it this color
why is it served at that place what does
it mean to that person like why did they
choose this
maybe that didn't go into it maybe they
were like i like that bottle that's what
i'm gonna use
you know like but as a person and also
humans just appreciate art and so when
you see something that's nice and
beautiful and it
um evokes emotion that's just like a
biological thing that i think that we
have so
i think that's why instagram gets our
attention because there's just all this
art to appreciate but all this stuff is
just pretty for our brains to look at
and it's not actually doing
anything for us
well okay so i was thinking you know the
the you know dopamine shortcut of laying
in bed and you get to experience
beauty like normally like before
technology before phones and you know
even before
let's say cameras and photos um you're
laying in your bed and you're just in
your environment so i feel like there's
a
in order to see beauty you have to seek
beauty
i feel like um before and so it would it
would motivate you to
leave your house to go on a hike to go
find these other things that other
artists are creating
and really really look for them so you
can have that experience but now we have
the shortcut like
oh i wanna i'm kind of feeling down and
i'm kind of feeling blah and so i'm
gonna go experience some beauty and you
click on your phone then you
your chemicals are just going off in
your head so it's it's
it's interesting to see the you know
there's so many benefits to social media
in our
are intertwining as humans with
technology but i really do enjoy looking
at the
hey how is this not helpful to me how is
this demotivating to me
yeah i think that um and so that's the
whole thing where
the um the humane technology movement
has asked everyone to delete their
social media
and i'm not that far because i think
social media is
great for a lot of reasons there are
just a few detrimental
um habits that we get from it that i
think should be eliminated if you're
conscious of them and so that mindless
scrolling is something that they
obviously
want us to do and that's not something
we need to do that was never something
humans did before that's never something
i did before
just mindlessly scrolling through my
phone like
no one's ever done that you never like
you
i always i grew up watching you know
like little einsteins and
informational videos and all those kinds
of things so like
whenever i was consuming digital
information it was teaching me something
i've never done this weird passive thing
where i'm just scrolling and scrolling
and like
i'll be working and my brain is bored of
the work i'm doing so i'm scrolling
and working like it doesn't it doesn't
make any sense
it's just it's a weird thing to do
and it's not productive and like think
about how much time you're taking away
from other things and
um i find myself you know when i'm
i get a i'll get an instagram
notification while i'm walking to my car
and then i'm looking at my phone while
walking through a parking lot like
that's not safe you're supposed to be
aware of your surroundings especially as
a woman like i'm supposed to be aware of
everything that's happening around me
like not looking at my phone because i
got an instagram notification that i can
look at
literally any other time and then when
you get a notification
you get sucked into whatever is
happening and i will tell you that the
getting sucked in thing doesn't happen
as often with the grayscale
that's not something yeah like i'll get
a message i'll go to check the message
and i'm like it's not interesting being
on here so
i'm off so well well i think even
bringing those
just you know bringing it to the
forefront of your attention and just
having that awareness of
you know i think we all have our little
habits so if we pull out our phone or we
get a text we get a notification we
respond to it and then
you know we got a few more minutes until
we're or we gotta we got 50 more feet
till we're at our car so let's click on
the instagram icon really quick and
scroll
so we can fill this gap of time yeah
yeah i mean i i do it all the time i'm
always trying to
explore within myself you know my
addictive tendencies when it comes to
social media and like what is this
validating within me
is this helpful um is it am i okay you
know and there's also a part with me
where i try to forgive myself and i try
to say like
hey it's okay to enjoy this thing that
you have right now it's okay like give
yourself the time
um give yourself five more minutes to do
this and then
put that put that line sinker in it um
something i wanted to switch over to
abrielle is something you you were
saying as you're walking you know
just as a woman to um you know be aware
of your surroundings like it's something
that
you would have to think of more often
often than i like i can be kind of
you know head in the clouds and not not
be
in the same headspace as you would be
you know trying to look out for yourself
and i i bring that up because i know
that you've taken
um women's self-defense classes right
yeah well it it has been women
self-defense but i also take
i take krav maga and the krav maga turns
into
women's self-defense classes that's
mixed martial arts technically
it's um it's what they train the israeli
defense forces in
it's uh it's i think it translates to
like
brutal street combat or something like
that
i don't know if that it translates to
that that's not the right word but
that's like what it's considered is
it's just kind of like the goal of krav
maga is to neutralize the threat
so we learn and i especially
love the women's self-defense classes
because we learn anything from
if someone comes and grabs your shirt
like how do you get out of that and
you know help yourself out of the
situation if someone my favorite
recently
um the instructor learned like a new
technique if someone grabs your hair
how to you know maneuver out of that um
if one of the women who was in there you
know
a lot of women would find themselves
like
on their back under another person and
how do you defend when another person is
on top of you and you're on the ground
things like that and it also just krav
maga
teaches more confidence
in that you can do something like
there are a lot of women who just when
anything would happen they may not think
to do
anything and krav maga just teaches you
that there are options
and there's a way to like stop analyze
choose what you're gonna do and move
forward within a split second
and i don't know how i would react in a
real situation
but i know that i know there are options
and i know that i've been told
when since i've started doing krav
when i'm in situations with people i
don't know i'm like
in a fighting stance i'm like ready to
go
because that's just like i i'm more
aware of myself
and i'm people are less likely to pick
on you
if you look stronger or if you look like
you know what you're doing or you look
like you're
no you're going somewhere like if you're
just walking slowly somewhere
someone can pick on you more than if
you're walking with purpose
so there are just things that we learn
like that um
but also like doing
any martial art i feel like would teach
your body that it can do something
the more often you punch the stronger
your wrists get
you know i've learned that my wrists are
stronger now because you're you're
punching and your wrist can't like
bend or whatever so it just has to be
strong
so there are those things that i learned
that i
i know i could hit someone with the
what is this the butt of your palm i
know i could yeah that's the butt
yeah the i don't know what is that
called i don't know whatever
yeah i feel like i've heard it called
the butt of your bomb that's the
scientific term
and something like that but i know that
you can like hit them in the bridge of
their nose and it hurts
i've also people we've worked with i've
taught them that you can take someone's
nose and
go like that and bring their head back
seems unpleasant
yeah it's very unpleasant they didn't
like it
um but there are just little small
things you can do to the body and they
they teach you those things and i'm
really happy to be able to do that
so yeah you know that reminds me just
the the level of preparation that brings
you for
you know i like it's not that you're
always guarded like you're always just
waiting for like any interaction so
you're just like
are you about to punch me because i'll
punch you first sort of thing um but it
it it just me
is this preparation uh what popped into
my mind was
uh kevin hart talking about he had
gotten a car wreck a while back ago
um the comedian kevin hart actor kevin
hart and he talked about how
him being in shape before the car wreck
happened
was his preparation for the car wreck
like so if he hadn't worked out before
if he wasn't an avid like
uh in in shape fit person then that car
wreck would have been a lot worse like
his body wouldn't have handled it as
much like his
um i don't remember exactly the extent
of his injuries but
him being fit before actually kind of
saved him in these injuries and so
that's just what pops into mind for that
it's kind of just this like it keeps you
in
optimal shape mentally like just knowing
hey if something does happen right now
i can handle it my body is trained for
it you know i don't even have to think
my body knows the reactive things
because i train them and i'd go to class
yeah something i that i encountered
recently i also teach acrobatics
and so i i lift weights and i go to the
gym a lot and i'm doing krav maga and
the gym supplements krav maga
um i have been
squatting higher weight recently
and then in acrobatics i just started
teaching the girls back handsprings and
so i'm having to catch these hundred
pound girls and flip them over
and i'm thinking thank god i can squat
higher than
your weight and i have built my arms a
little bit so i can
hold you and i can pick these girls up
no problem and flip them over
like i every i think you know working
out supplements everything it's just
people with back pain don't work out and
if you have back pain working out
normally helps back pain there's just
you know i used to get a lot of knots in
my back and it was from my back being
out of shape
you know so there's yeah dude i
i think i'm always
i'm always you know preaching to the
choir likely and just yelling at nobody
from a hill but
i'm always just trying to convince
people to work out and move and stretch
because to me i think that our society
has this thing where
working out is to burn calories if
you're fat it's like no no
it's has all these there's millions of
other benefits it makes you
feel better it increases your ability it
strengthens your immune system
it strengthens your respiratory system
like there's all these things that
um if you look at your body as uh you
know
holistically affecting your everyday
life which it does
a hundred percent it's not just oh i'm
getting kind of chubby
oh i've got a vacation in four months so
i'm gonna start working out or
oh i ate a piece of cake and so i'm over
my calorie count so that's why i'm going
to work out for me it's just like
there's so much preparation it helps
your mental health to work out to
just move get your cerebral spine fluid
moving around daily it helps with
i have a lot of inflammation i get
neural inflammation which is a lot of my
effects of when it comes to depression
and just
breathing doing yoga stretching it out
10 minutes 20 minutes that helps me like
remove some of that inflammation so yeah
i think um
like just all the all the different
facets of our life that are positively
effective by
being active some form of activity and i
know right now just to kind of
put it put a stick in this part any
listener right now kova times are weird
all right like our gyms are canceled the
council right now i don't know where
it's how it is over
with you abroad but they just shut off
florida's open
florida oh yeah you guys can do whatever
you want yeah i mean
i have to wear my mask to walk into the
gym and get my temperature taken
but then masked off we're good to go
there's supposed to be social distancing
there's not yeah it's so hard it's so
hard to
to compare like what's what's the right
thing to do like there's so many
humans are so complicated we can't it's
not just a yes or no a good or a bad
thing but
i don't know either way i i think that
anybody especially in these
times get active like get out of your
house a lot of us are on our computers
more
a lot of us like you said you know so
many people
complain about back pain or complain
about knee pain or ankle pain or
or hips hurt or my neck hurts or all
these things tired all the time
tired all the time for sure and there's
something about it's like our ego
protects us because our ego is like well
i want to
justify why i'm doing what i'm doing um
and so you you suggest um i i have many
people in my life where
um there will be those complaints said
to me and i'm like why are you
stretching are you doing this like oh
well i got this injury and i can't and
um no i i don't i don't do that or or
whatever
like but we've got to take control and
take
um responsibility for our physical
health i think
my favorite is like when you ask someone
if they drink water and they're like oh
i don't need that much water
that's that's what is that what yeah
like it's one of my favorites
how do you know man like how do you like
you know everything about the interior
of your body like as your body's
processing the water you think you
consciously do that or something like
you're
sending your water dehydrated at
different parts of the day
you can drink a lot of water in the
morning and be like yeah i drank
two glasses of water this morning and
you can feel great and dehydrated for
three to four hours but like if you
don't drink any
water for the rest of the day you're
going to be dehydrated
by the end of the night and i think i
heard some statistic
75 of americans are dehydrated
think about how tired that makes you
think about how
hungry that makes you and then it makes
you eat more and then you're overweight
and then you don't work out because
you're overweight
and you know you're tired because you're
overweight because you retired from not
drinking water
it just i don't work as well i get
headaches how many people have headaches
from drinking water and they don't know
it
they would rather take an ibuprofen or
in a leaf before drinking a glass of
water
absolutely and it's just it's crazy to
me but
i think going back to working out
working out helps me just because i have
so much energy
i'm just a different person like i'm not
necessarily crazy
but i'm just like a little bit more
irritable i'm a little bit more
um like
let's go do this thing i'm a little bit
more a little there like
there's when i go to the gym and i push
myself
and i get that sweat in and i've
challenged myself for the day i'm good
there's i'm just chill to be around
someone argue i'm not i guess but no i'm
totally with you i
like getting that it really helps the
mental like you can wake up and you got
brain fog and you kind of got scattered
thoughts
but you go in you exert yourself and you
pay attention and you do
you do your job you do your workout and
then at the end it's just like all right
now i'm calm i'm ready
i'm more precise than i was before um i
think
so many people would benefit from just
physical activity it helps us it helps
us all a lot
and i was telling you too when i was
going through that whole thing like
there are a lot of things that could
have made me feel
depressed and anxious and given me all
of those feelings because
when i start working a lot i eat less i
sleep less and
those kinds of things having low blood
sugar and not eating enough can
definitely make you feel tired make you
feel depressed and increase
anxiety not sleeping makes you tired
makes you depressed can increase anxiety
feeling anxiety and having experience
with anxiety and then
feeling anxiety again from something i
don't really associate with
like not knowing where my anxiety is
coming from or maybe feeling overwhelmed
and thinking
associating my anxiety with my feeling
of overwhelm
it's not um it just kind of contributes
to
more anxiety like why am i feeling
anxious why am i this why am i that and
then i just spiral into anxiety and
depression
when like maybe i just needed to eat a
hamburger like who knows like
eat a hamburger and drink a glass of
water maybe that's what it was
when i was growing up i was very thin
and
um i would always have a lot of
headaches and i didn't eat very much
because i just wasn't hungry
but what i realized and it came from
talking to my aunt about what her
daughter does about
my um my cousin what my cousin does is
she doesn't eat big meals but she would
eat every two hours
so i started doing that and i had less
headaches i was less upset
i was less crazy i was less this i was
less than it all was diet related
so i can't imagine how many people have
problems
and feel these certain ways and they
just have poor nutrition
poor nutrition poor workout schedule
poor
um you know like not drinking enough
water
just not doing themselves right and i
can't imagine
the difference it would make for people
yeah for real i you know it's
i always encourage people to really find
what works for you you know get in tune
with how do i feel do i feel okay
and like how have i felt the last couple
days and why is it and what time of
night breakfast and all this for me
the the act of fasting
is what seems to be the absolute best
for me um
like i you know there's there's been
stages in my life where
eating every couple hours definitely has
been the best for me
but then that that stops working or that
stops that
um allows me to be too lenient on going
to vending machines or you know
eating eating crappy food more often so
what i found that works for me
um over the last like a year and a half
or so is
fasting intermittent fasting so i
basically have like a feeding window i'm
eating during these four hours or i'm
just eating this one big meal and then
i'm done
um yeah but yeah i i think getting in
touch with
you know you're like okay when i eat
more often i have less headaches
cool you know i think getting to that
problem-solving mindset of
there's an answer here is very helpful
rather than just
i always have headaches and so i just
taken a leave and it helps because we we
like to alleviate our symptoms but not
get to the root cause of the problems
it's just kind of
how we've been raised in the western
society i feel like it's like when you
have
a problem you just you go to the doctors
and they they find a way to fix it and
if not there's there's a pill that'll
fix that thing but
a lot of our problems are symptomatic of
our lifestyle and of what we're not
doing or what we're doing too much
i think that also comes with i just
bought a supplement recently
and the reason i bought it was because i
got sucked into this
20-minute ad for it and i
just started listening to it and i was
like okay i'm hooked like
i understand the marketing aspects that
i'm being addressed by right now but
i'll just
listen to you go ahead and she's just
telling me all of these
reasons i need to take her supplement
and why i feel the way i do and i'm like
okay you got me i'll spend the 50
whatever it is on your supplement and
see if it helps but
the supplement is for bloating
um more energy and uh
it's supposed to it's supposed to
decrease floating
increase energy and a third thing
and so then i bought the supplement
because i was like no harm in trying
but why do i need that supplement like
why
if i'm experiencing bloating like what
am i eating that's making me bloated
if i don't have enough energy what am i
eating that's making me feel like i
don't have enough energy or what else
could i be doing that could give me more
energy am i not sleeping enough am i not
getting all of these things so
you know i found that i'm not lactose
intolerant but i don't
react well to milk if i drink milk i get
very bloated
i eat yogurt i get very bloated i used
to eat yogurt every single day
and i used to feel bloated every single
day so am i going to take a supplement
to decrease bloating or am i going to
eliminate yogurt
you know so there's just these things
and i feel like
people don't realize them like going to
the gym and
taking supplements and stuff like do you
need them how much do you need them
if you're lifting heavy weights
obviously like the normal human body
won't be able to do that or support that
and you need to add a little bit extra
but if you're just like a normal person
that's just going
to do some cardio like i don't think you
need
bcaas and creatine
and although there are benefits to
taking creatine i take creatine it's
good for women it's good for men it's
good for a ton of reasons like
do we actually need these things taking
all these vitamins like if we
if we just ate the right things would we
get the right amount of vitamins from
our food you know
yeah i mean that's what supplements are
it's like it's
it's supplementing something that you're
that should be in your diet
um i think our our our modern our modern
food system is just not actually really
designed for
optimal humans you know it's uh it's
our economy really you know think think
of fast food like i'm a sucker for fast
food man
i know that it doesn't always serve me
well but it helps when i'm like
okay i'm like two days ago i went to
chick-fil-a because i worked up in
seattle
um and i had to go like jet back and and
get to my
um other job and i i didn't prep
before you know and so i i got fast food
so it's like
it helps fill this need of needing some
food in between so i can work more
but we got to look at our lives as work
is is a facet of my life health is also
a facet of my life how i feel
allows me to work better so if i'm
eating fast food six times a week then
i can't show up mentally and
and optimally do my job and
i think with quarantine we're learning
that there are more facets in our life
than just
work and things like that like i think
that's something i've talked to you
about um that through quarantine and
being locked down and there was a
specific time when no one could go out
and no one could work and there was
nothing to do and
i just learned who i am and what my
schedule is and what i need
things i like to eat you know like what
makes me
feel fulfilled during the day do i like
to read
am i more into screens am i more do i
like to journal what do i like to learn
about
how do i spend my time when i'm just by
myself
being me and then once work started to
kick up like
how do i incorporate back into my
schedule
how much work do i really want to put
into my day
and i'm so lucky that i'm a contractor
and i'm not an employee and i'm not in a
position to where i'm
scrounging for money and things like
that so where
i can say from these hours to these
hours i'm
working and the rest of the time like
working out doing laundry cooking
learning
you know like i dedicate a chunk of my
day to work
but that's only a part of my day i also
go to the gym i go to krav maga
i hang out with my boyfriend i talk to
my family i talk to my friends i talk to
my extended family
i read something i'm watching a movie
i'm watching a video like
i'm fulfilling myself in other ways that
doesn't just come from work and i think
that's something that i've
i've just realized and learned that
work isn't my whole life you know right
yeah i mean so you're
i mean you're doing all these things now
but i feel like even before the pandemic
you have
you have a huge work ethic um you have a
huge drive
i mean like does this come from just
knowing like hey i want to be as most
self-actualized as i possibly can
or did you have do you have somebody
like inspiring in your life that maybe
when you were younger
like instilled these things in you like
where does your hard work ethic come
from
yeah i definitely had my dad my dad
worked a lot
i don't know that it necessarily was
inspiring
because he just you know he was that dad
who works so much and he
traveled for work he he sold microscopes
but he sold
microscopes like universities and big
scientists so he was doing the big bill
ones that's a cool
job yeah he's he's a sick guy he's cool
um but so like he knows
he would be the person they call and
would know all the specific
things about a microscope and uh he
would go to conventions and travel to
the netherlands and he would always be
in a different city and i feel like
when i was growing up there was a lot of
him traveling like
he'd be gone for valentine's day he'd be
gone for my mom's birthday
if he's home he was always in the office
and we've talked about it since
he's retired and you know i'm older and
i know how to analyze things and i'm
emotionally intelligent
so when he sees me working i ask him
what it was like to be working when his
family was eating dinner he's working in
the car while we're driving somewhere
he's working this time he's always on
the phone he leaves
thanksgiving to answer the phone he goes
up into his office and i don't see him
all day and then he comes down in a row
because he hasn't gotten dressed at all
and
you know that's what i see and that's
kind of the way i am too
but that's that's kind of where i got
that from but
i have to i have to know that i am
fulfilled too because
work is not my whole life and when i die
like
when i die i don't want to say like i
did my job
you know i want my goal in life is to be
the best in i want to be a well-rounded
person
i want to be the best in everything that
i can do i want to be
a great friend i want to be a great
partner i want to be great at
communicating i want to be great at
cooking
i want to be a great manager i want to
be a great employee i want to be a great
um athlete i want to be a great i want
to be great at flexibility like i just
want to be the best at everything
and i recognize that i can't be the best
at everything like
i'm not very good at dancing and a lot
of people will attest to that
i'm not very good at dancing i have no
intentions of being a great dancer but i
i intend on getting better
um but i just wanna i
like i want to be a total package i want
to live my life fully
i want my life to be filled with
love and light and just
the best things i can find so
i don't how did we get there i don't
even know
just kind of where you got that work
ethic i feel like the the
you're on you're on the pursuit of your
best self like no
knowing that maybe you'll never reach it
but i think
knowing that that's your path you know
is
is bound to give you the best life you
could ask for
right you know when it really is it's
the pursuit of my best self and it's
i am a firm believer that there's no new
year's resolutions there's a new day
resolution there's no like
i'm going to start this thing but i'm
going to start january 1st i got it like
start tomorrow start today start right
now like when are you going to start
eating healthy go to the grocery store
and start for dinner like there's no
like why tomorrow you just you've
like time is a perception so like why
are you going to start
at a certain time or at the beginning of
a week that is a fake
thing like that's only a concept like
why don't you just start right now your
body
is bad right now why don't you start now
you don't like your job now why don't
you quit now like why are you going to
wait
until you get some promotion or you make
a certain amount of money or you get
this whatever
obviously there's going to be some
reason maybe in someone's life that that
makes sense but
you're just doing the same thing over
and over and over again like why are you
going to wait until january 1st to
change
change tomorrow change today changed
right now
that's that's a huge part of who i am so
i'm just i'm constantly evolving and i
see things posted online that
say you know i talk to people in
my past and they don't recognize who i
am because i've evolved to another level
and that's that's my experience all the
time anyone i talk to from my childhood
i'm so different i want different things
i speak differently i hold myself
differently i feel
about myself differently people used to
think i was a certain way i'm not
anymore i have to correct them i
i don't feel that way i'm this and that
and this and that like i am evolving
exponentially every day that i wake up
and um what i started doing recently is
i started journaling in the morning
i just reflect back on what i did
yesterday and how i felt about it and
then my goals for
today and um what i'm thankful for
so that really gives me a chance to
i do it right when i wake up so 6 45 in
the morning
and i don't check any of my
notifications in the morning i just get
right
into my journal i reflect on everything
i did
and actually one thing that i realized
is
so many good things happen to me in a
day
there are too many for me to put in like
a little concise
journal i don't want to be too long and
i don't want to take too long doing it i
take about 15 minutes to do it
or shorter if i can but i don't want it
to be a long thing that takes my time
otherwise i won't do it
so i wanted to be concise and i realized
like if i'm talking about all the great
things that happened the day before
because i do want to focus on the good
things
i can mention the bad things but i want
i want the purpose of the journal
to be to teach my brain to think
more positively not that it thinks
negatively
but we all have a tendency to lean
towards the negative things you know
like the one negative thing that
happened during the day
we sort of lean towards that rather than
focus on
i woke up today i had groceries in my
fridge i have enough money to buy more
if i need to i had a great breakfast
i had a great workout i had i worked on
a project that i love because i work in
a job that i love
like i get to do different things every
day there's variety i
love what i do i love the people i work
with i love the conversations i have
got a nice email um
went to crawf had a great class and then
i got to see my boyfriend and he was
great and
talk to my family and they're all great
everyone's healthy nobody's injured no
one has covered
like everything is super good in my life
i come home to
my cats my cats are great i have my own
apartment that i can afford
i feel like i live a great life i'm
really happy
obviously i want more like i'd rather
not live in this apartment my whole life
um but like i want a dog like i have
more things that i want to do i want to
make more money i want to
invest i want i want more for myself but
i think where i am right now
i'm 25 years old i think i'm in a pretty
good spot
and then just trying to list all of the
good things in a day like
that's what i'm grateful for is i have
so many things to be grateful for i
can't even list them out
shortly briefly because it's something
that's so interesting
the the journaling has really um taught
me to focus and
uh it's helped like uh reflect on myself
and my experiences
yeah yeah i mean it's because when you
journal you kind of realize
because you're someone who's so aware of
your thoughts and aware of what's going
on
um it's kind of
we get into these moods where
we can forget about all that other stuff
like something kind of
you know big could happen or something
we could just kind of get into this
thought loop of like
man i'm not where i want to be in this
aspect of my life and blah blah and like
before you know it
you're kind of just spiraling and you um
you're kind of down on yourself
and when you journal and when you show
gratitude
for what you do enjoy in your life what
is going well in your life
it has this it has this great way of um
kind of snapping you out of your own
[__] sometimes
but i also think that doing it more
often teaches your brain to
do it more often like they can speak it
yeah
take it till you make it just so that's
what was wrong with me that
that few weeks recently ago um
i told you i had talked to my personal
trainer and i was feeling that i
was feeling like i couldn't work out or
i was bad at working out and like what
does that even mean you know
but i was forgetting my gratitude i
i am forgetting that i have two legs and
i have two arms and i woke up this
morning and i have
the financial ability to have a gym
membership and i'm able to
my gym is open i live in a state where
my gym can be open
i can work out i there are where we live
in a time where there's plenty of gym
equipment
i'm not you know stuck waiting for
someone my gym is big enough
i live in a place where i have options
of going to different gyms
like thank god i can work out i'm
i'm forgetting that gratitude you know
i'm feeling bad like i'm not good at it
i'm not
like what am i not good at i'm not good
at lifting something up and throwing it
down like what does that mean for me why
am i feeling that way and compared to
what so
i was forgetting my gratitude and i was
comparing myself to other people that
aren't me yeah what is your
if you had to
like like the the strength that you have
the the feelings
within you that you're like okay i'm
proud of these things within myself i'm
glad that i'm able to
see um you know be emotionally aware be
emotionally intelligent
these these areas
how how would you suggest to someone who
maybe they've been on these loops of um
not being very nice to themselves not
being very grateful for what they do
have
um you know we all get kind of caught up
in in the muck of it sometimes like how
would you
what advice would you give to someone
who you know it's time for them to build
some strength it's time for them to
build some
um self persev perseverance you know um
how would you inspire people it's
repetition
and it's recognizing it's perspective
it's recognition
and perspective there is you have to
have perspective
because you i
i was listening to something recently
and i think it was joe rogan
that it was um the worst thing that
happens some
to someone can be the worst thing that
happens to them
but it's not bad compared to what
happened to someone else
and so you know like i say i'm i'm so
grateful to live
in my apartment i'm so grateful to wake
up you have to have that perspective
like there are hundreds of thousands of
people who die
every day or just don't wake up i've had
friends who you know get into drinking
or drugs or
they are just casually on sleeping pills
they you know like they
have to take medicine to go to sleep
they had one night where they
went out and drank a lot and then they
took their sleeping pill just like
normal and then they never woke up again
and so i have that perspective just when
i wake up in the morning
thank goodness the sun is shining
through my window like i've
i'm oriented in a way that however my
apartment is that the sun can come in my
apartment and on the opposite side where
it sets on that side you know like
i there are just when you have the
perspective
you're able to recognize all those
little blessings
and i hope to god i never
lose my gratitude and so that's why
they're sorry alarm going off that's why
there's
moments where i feel like i'm forgetting
my gratitude
and i i hope i never do because it's
something that people don't have and
that's also something i'm grateful for
is that i have my gratitude
right um because there's just really
there are people who are just
grumpy you know about living their life
and
i hate my job and i hate this thank god
you have a job
can you imagine the amount of people
right now who don't have a job
it's just it's so sad and the amount of
people who get caught up in the news and
then they're so stressed out and they're
so anxious and
this is happening and this is happening
and this is happening but it's not
actually affecting you
and your life is pretty good and you're
healthy
and there's not a lot that's going on
that's negative in your life it's just
that one
thing that happened to you that took 10
minutes of your day that was bad
yeah yeah uh um duncan tressel has this
little rant that he goes off that just
it struck me so hard
um basically there's probably some
[__]
who's out there in the woods right now
with no cell phone staring at a
beautiful waterfall who has no idea
how pissed off he's supposed to be right
now yeah you know like
it's it's it's just this reminder that
yes these things that you've been
focusing on like maybe they have some
truth to them maybe they are
um you know bits of information
but are they helpful to your life um are
they the only truth
um you know just as much as like all
these things that have been going on
um in the political world with all this
divisiveness
all this um you know separation all this
argument
that we've gotten into over the last you
know four or five years
it's that would still you don't have to
interact with that like other that could
exist for other people and you could
turn your phone off and go look at a
waterfall
you know it's it's not the only reality
so a lot of times we need to
be able to take take a little stock of
how much time
am i investing in my am i investing my
intention
in the correct things do these things
that i'm investing my attention in
benefit me in the future is this helpful
to
you know the the person that i want to
be the person that i strive to be the
person that i hope to
you know someday accomplish or lean
towards
there's a difference between i feel like
a lot of people don't want to dwell on
their thoughts and dwell on things like
that but there's a difference between
you know functional analysis and
dwelling and that was something that i
had to figure out because
i was talking recently about you know
like maybe i
i do think a lot about stuff but maybe
i'm over
thinking and over analyzing you know
like the way that i think about
something and i think about the way i
think about something and then i think
about the way i think about thinking
about something
that's just fine maybe
i don't need to do that um
but so you have to just be aware of like
what you're saying
why why did that happen why am i
thinking about it
do i need to think about it or is it
useless to think about i
i know something um that i've had to
teach myself in the last
few years is that
that feeling of when you've either upset
someone
or you haven't upset someone or you
might you said something to someone
maybe um
and you think they're upset with you and
you just sit there thinking like
did i say the wrong thing did i do this
did i do that are they feeling bad like
oh my god what are they
are they crying are they are they mad
like i'm crying because i think they're
mad or i think that they reacted this
way i think they feel this way
none of that actually exists and i had
to teach myself that
that when i'm sitting on the other side
of my phone my device
you know like how was that message
received are they mad
are they do they feel this none of that
exists until
someone says they're mad or until
someone acts like they're mad like
normally they would be talking to you
sending me smiley faces or
saying good morning or whatever or like
with in the case of my brother like
normally we text a bunch if
if he's not communicating with me at all
if someone's not communicating with you
at all or if they
specifically say what you said was
messed up and i'm mad at you
there is no reason to have stress or
anxiety
about a situation that you don't know
the outcome of or you don't know
the status of you have to ask yeah
that's super powerful actually
i get in the mindset or i get in the
habit a lot of asking a lot of questions
and it's
a little bit you know like i i ask
i ask a lot of questions about like
where a person is and i know
my boyfriend specifically says like
don't ask me like i'm good like it
unless i have a problem like i'm good
and so i figured out that
and i've talked to a lot of other girls
who their guys are just like
don't ask me i'm good yeah yeah like
guys are just like
we're good unless liberty say we're not
good like i don't know and girls were
like how are you feeling how did you
feel five seconds ago
how were you this morning did you change
yeah i mean i hey i can vouch for that i
have i'm definitely more in touch with
my feminine side i was raised by
um a lot of women on my younger ages um
so i'm definitely like that
i've kind of had to learn those own
lessons myself to look at this guy he's
just so
cute i'm cute um so i i feel like that
leads right into
we did mention the word projection
before i feel like that's kind of what
that is you know a lot of times we
project our own
insecurities on uh what we believe other
people to be thinking about us
it absolutely is and i that's another
thing i realize is a lot of
almost like 80 percent of my interaction
with people is
projection of how i'm feeling so you
know i will
something will happen in a situation and
i'm like oh
should i have said that now i feel bad
now i feel stressed now i feel anxious
do you feel anxious do you feel stressed
why are you upset
now you're acting weird why are you
upset and it's like
they weren't acting weird it's all me
it's all me being
projecting onto them or why don't why
aren't you
so happy why aren't you and they're like
you're bombarding me with questions
about why i'm upset
right right when they're just they
weren't even thinking about any of those
things they're probably just dealing
with their own intricate things and
trying not to project their own [__] you
know
that's right i told my brother when he
went to college he
you know he didn't want to go to the
grocery store because he was afraid of
like what people
were going to see him buying and i'm
like oh dude people are
thinking so much about their own
problems they have no idea what's your
in your shopping cart they don't care
they don't care whether you bought
that brand of cheese or that brand of
cheese like everyone's so
into themselves like who's gonna pay
attention to you
isn't that the realest [__] though like
i've got compassion for your brother
because like i'll catch myself doing
same things like that i'm like well
you know i try to put out this this very
healthy food conscious person
on the internet and so if someone sees
me buy a bag of doritos i'm going to
feel guilty enough to explain to myself
or whatever like it's it's this weird
thing we we do to ourselves when it's
nobody would ever give a damn what's in
my grocery cart it's just me
everybody is so busy worrying about
themselves they're not worrying about
you
it's so true but the projection is it's
in
every situation but i feel it
now that i'm more aware of it it's
something that you have it's just
something that you have to be aware of
but you can't be aware that you're
projecting onto people if you aren't
aware of your own emotions
and i am so aware of myself like
i know that this situation happened i'm
reacting
poorly to it is this person actually
upset with me
or am i projecting my feeling onto them
so what i had to learn first was to stop
thinking about
maybe they're upset with me maybe
they're not because that is just
i would spend hours and nights and days
thinking about how i thought the other
person felt
i think you feel this way not that you
actually feel that way
i think that you think that way or i
think that you're thinking these
thoughts
not that you actually are not that
you've actually ever communicated to me
that you would be thinking those
thoughts or that you've said anything
that might hint that you're thinking
those thoughts
i just think you're thinking them and so
i'm just gonna be upset that i think
you're thinking something
just a huge waste of time and something
that took me a long time to get over
but now that i don't do that like
it's just sounds freeing it's so
freeing it's just a breath of fresh air
to just
you know like uh i have younger people
who i talk to
my brother his friends people in his
circle i don't want this person to think
this of me so i'm not going to do this
or this person i think they're mad at me
blah blah blah
will have whole conversations about what
they think this person thinks
and i'm like you have no idea you didn't
talk to them did they say that
then don't be upset about it you know so
you have to first understand
what you're feeling to be able to
understand that you're projecting
and then i feel like there's even people
who might deny that they're projecting
you know
like oh they they didn't
text me this thing so i know that they
are upset
but maybe they didn't text that thing
because you know they dropped their
phone
or they are doing something else or
literally any other reason
in life yeah yeah th this whole like uh
like if if you if you wanted me in your
life you would
um you would pay attention or you would
give me your time or whatever it is it's
like man maybe they're just like trying
to navigate maybe they like you just
fine they enjoy talking to you they
enjoy hanging out with you it's just
you know they just had some [__] they
had to take care of or they dropped
their phone in a cup of water or
whatever you know i'm absolutely guilty
of it where
someone will text me and i won't answer
for a week and it's not like
i don't like you it's not that you're um
not a priority
it's not that you know whatever like you
i think that you think
it's just it's i open something and then
i do something else and i get distracted
and that's that's it and then 10 other
people text me that day and then your
text goes to the bottom of the list and
i think about you a week later and then
i'm like oh my god
i never texted that person back you know
what's funny is i feel like the
my relationship with with all of you
guys over in florida is kind of like
that
um megan and i megan and i have go
through these things of like every
every couple months like we won't talk
for a few months and then for the span
of a few months we'll basically send
postcards back
where it's like we're kind of talking
about six different subjects
and we'll just paragraph them and then
hit send
you know like um but it's you know
there's nothing that says that
just because we have technology and
we're available at all times like just
because
at this very moment i can call you and
you could pick up and within three
seconds we can be connected
through our ears doesn't mean that we
need to be giving away our time all the
time so i think it's okay actually to
not always be available in that way you
know form
relationships um where you know it's
just an understanding where you and your
friend are like hey we just hit each
other back every couple days
sometimes i don't hit you back but that
doesn't mean that you can't hit me with
a new subject next week
or you know bring it back up it's not
that i'm mad it's not that i'm anything
a hundred percent yeah we um it's it's
you know
navigating this adding technology to
human emotion and what human feeling
really is
is something we got to be patient with
ourselves about and forgive ourselves
and not be so overly analytical you know
i i love being overly analytical but
when it comes to trying to figure out
what other people are thinking good luck
yeah it also makes me i'm more conscious
of the way i'm communicating now
because i'm a very private person
but i'm open to being vulnerable
so i don't like to
uh talk about what's going on in my life
but if you
ask me i'm very open uh so
like i want there's been a lot of stuff
with work going on and i have to
you know obviously do my work but
there's a lot of other things in my life
that are going on that's preventing me
from doing all of my work
or doing it as quickly as i wanted to do
it and
i'm not going to come and be like oh
i didn't finish it because i have this
going on and this going on and this
going on and this going on those are all
true
but i'm just going to get my job done
and i'm just gonna do it and i'm not
gonna say anything like
i keep my stuff to myself i'm not gonna
you know shout at the rooftops what i'm
doing but if you ask me
what i'm doing why i'm doing it how i'm
doing it i'm happy to you know
talk about it um where did that come
from what did you say
there was something else i had but i
don't remember because i don't know how
i got there
you were talking about
um man no i'm spacing it usually i'm
good to give you the cue
right away
i get that though i mean we're going off
going off projection and trying to
figure out what other people are
thinking about
it's communication and then it was um i
was talking about being a private person
but i'm open
um i don't know what that is
whatever um asynchronous this is the end
of it yeah
um i was talking to my brother recently
and he was
on the phone with someone while in the
car with me
and while he's on the phone he's getting
all these notifications
and he puts his phone on speaker and
it's like hold on i can't talk
and then i have to answer all these
things and if i if i don't answer
they're gonna get mad at me and
okay i can talk now hold on i just got
another notification i'm sitting next to
him in the car like
are we gonna talk what about me
wow what a stressful life that a lot of
young people are feeling the need to
live
right like how much stress and anxiety
do you have because you think that this
is
synchronous like it's asynchronous you
don't need to answer you don't
it's just like an email it's a text is
just like an email unless you're
i don't know like i i want to say unless
you're in a conversation with someone
then you know like it's it's synchronous
but
even then like if you're you're saying
like what are you up to today
i don't have to answer you for hours i
can answer later and be like oh i did
this i did this i did this would you do
today
and then you can answer me in two days
and be like i don't remember but today i
did this like
yeah it doesn't have to be yeah i i have
i have one of my friends sweetest soul
ever but she was talking it makes me
think of um
you know she's she was talking to this
new guy and
there was a moment where she mentioned
like so i waited a couple hours to text
him back or i waited or whatever
and it's like intentionally do that it's
like man if you feel like immediately
you you were excited to talk to them
respond as fast as you want bro
like don't you don't have to calculate
all these things um you don't you it's
at the same time you don't have to feel
guilty about immediately responding like
sometimes dude it's just overwhelm like
it's just like man i just don't know if
i have
i'm not able to be present with what i
need to do in my life right now and
respond to all these people at this
moment and that's okay it's really not a
big deal
and most of the time if you're just real
with the people on the other end
and say like hey i'll hit you back later
or
you know you hit him two days two days
after and you're like hey sorry
appreciate you waiting whatever it is
just just be where you are
with with your attention on that thing
i don't even apologize anymore because
like that's just who i
am like i'm not going to sit there i
might sit there for
a while and text you but like i can't do
that i have
other things to do and so if i don't
answer
just assume that i'm going to eventually
like right
and they get them yeah they get it and
so i don't apologize for who i am and i
think it's really important to be
who you are in all the situations and so
for that person who doesn't
text back intentionally because they
don't want to seem xyz they don't want
to seem needy they don't want to seem
whatever they want to seem strong they
want to seem whatever
like you should be exactly who you are
in all situations and i learned that i
learned that unfortunately
from my last relationship where i was
disloyal and
i didn't tell him about it and he said i
much
i would have rather you told me so that
i could make a decision
rather than you making the decision for
us
and us moving forward based on the
decision you made like
let me know who you are and what's going
on so that i can make the decision for
myself
and that really opened the door for me
to be
to understand that like i'm gonna be
exactly who i
am in all situations and everyone else
can have their own
reaction to it have their own perception
of it
receive it differently like i'm just
gonna be who i am i'm never gonna act
like
i'm not i'm never gonna act less needy
than i am
or more needy than i am or like someone
that i'm not like
i'm always gonna come into a situation
there's a lot of times in our work where
i'm supposed to email nicely and i don't
and it's just that's not who i
am like i'm not gonna act like someone
i'm not there's
i do a lot of the hard stuff for our
company because
i'm the person who can do the hard stuff
like i i
have the hard conversations and i crack
the whip on the people who need it
because that's the kind of person i
am i'm not the nice cuddly oh you didn't
do the thing like it's okay
we don't need it we just wait for you to
do it like
there's no i don't have those bones in
my body
and i'm not gonna act like i do i'm not
gonna i'm not gonna apologize for myself
i'm not gonna
apologize for if in a situation i'm
doing so many things and i forget my
manners like
i really like to have manners and i
that's the part of being well-rounded
like i'd like to be a well-mannered
person but if i'm just doing so many
things and i forget my manners like i'm
not gonna say sorry like i just
i forgot to say thank you i appreciated
whatever you did but i forgot to say
thank you
that's just it is what it is and i
really feel that that
comes with the authenticity that comes
with emotional intelligence but it comes
from being comfortable with who you are
i'm just going to be exactly who i am in
every situation all the time
right yeah i mean i i think the just the
term allowing your own authentic
authenticity is what what comes up like
just allow it this is who i am
um i think that you're i think you're i
mean i don't know you kind of
you paint yourself out to be like some
cold hard cold hard
mean direct person or something though i
feel like you you are good at
you know even if you are dealing with
your own thing and you are still being
your authentic self you're still good in
those moments at
serving the purpose of the person that
you're talking to like i feel like
you're
you like you you understand the types of
direction that i need
in in through an email like as like you
know because you you are
it's not so much just like this is
exactly black and white how it goes
you're dealing with creative
people and when you're dealing with art
artistic people and creative people
you kind of have to have a different
approach and i feel like you you wrangle
that really well
you're able to be direct in yourself but
as
as someone who's on the other end of
that email as a creative person whose
mind just doesn't work exactly how other
people's do
i feel like you look for that and you
account for that
well it's like i said i have to
understand people who i'm working with
and so i have to
part of me has to become you i have to
think about how you're receiving an
email so like there are certain things
for different people who i know
that work like i know you specifically
like a lot of direction and deadlines
and so when i give you a deadline and
give you here's my vision
i know that's helpful for you there are
other people um
like when i used to send out flight
information and things like that i would
ask you to approve a flight and then you
would say i approve and then i would
book your flight
what my interpretation of that whole
charade was was that when you approved a
flight i booked it no communication was
necessary
there was someone else that we worked
with that was like it'd be nice to
receive like a confirmation email but
you did it
and i was like i never thought of that i
just assumed like i booked your flight
you said yes so i did it like why
wouldn't you think that i did it
but so you know i'm conscious of that
and so i send that out for everyone who
might need it like
i'd haven't talked to everyone but maybe
there are other people who also have
that concern so i just send one out to
everyone
and so i'm just very conscious of that
with each and every person i talk to is
that
everyone's different and you have to
kind of you have to mold
a little bit of yourself in those
situations but you should never
not be who you are you know love that
love that um gabrielle we're getting up
here a little bit in time
i want to ask you two questions to end
it off and then after that i want to
make sure everybody knows where to find
you where to find your next projects
kind of what you have going on in your
world so the questions that i was
thinking of um
something that i i really enjoy asking
other people is what's the legacy
that you want to leave like when you
think about legacy um like when you
leave this earth whenever whatever comes
next for
you know your life being what's the
legacy that you want to live and then
also
if you don't have to intertwine these
questions but you could if you'd like
um what does the world need more of
right now
um i won't intertwine this and i think
my legacy is that i want to be
i want to raise kids who are more open
more accepting
more loving more full of light more
emotionally intelligent
and you know smart i want to raise those
type of kids
i want that energy projected into the
world i want my legacy to be
just that overall light and positivity
and any
positive impact i can have in anyone's
life i want
that i just want in every situation i
can i want to make someone's life better
a piece of the world better any part of
any situation i can
better i just feel like i have so much
when i
feel feelings i feel them so hard
when i feel love i'm exploding with love
when i feel
sadness i'm just so sad when i see
tragedy happen i'm so sad for the people
who are affected by it like
i just i feel the energy of everything
and so i just want everything to be a
little bit
better by my presence i just want to be
able to interject just that little bit
of positivity
and then what do i think the world needs
more of
i think the world needs more
um introspectiveness
i think more people need to be aware of
themselves
aware of what they're doing aware of
how what how what they're doing
affects other people aware that
what you're doing might affect people
and that's not necessarily your problem
um people react to everything their own
way and that could be on themselves but
they also need to be aware of how
they're reacting and why i think
people just i i know people who are very
emotionally intelligent and very
intelligent people
that just kind of don't understand
themselves
or maybe suppress themselves or
um you know just they i think that they
have feelings that maybe they're not
feeling or something um
but then i also have people i know that
are very
they think about things just the same
way i do and when we have these
conversations it's just about
us and our philosophy and why we do
things the way that we do
so i feel like communication between
people will be better if we understand
ourselves better
more communication more honesty more on
authenticity
not following these brands not trying to
be like you are on social media just
loving yourself for who you are and
realizing what that means and realizing
that
to love yourself is to not be a good
person all the time and be
the best and be you know all these great
things that it can
you can have flaws and you can be bad at
all of these lists of things and like
that's who you are
i like for instance i know i'm not good
at being overly
beautiful in my emails and stuff but
like that's who i am
and i have to love myself for that i was
raised to be a blunt woman and
my mom is the same way she will tell you
exactly what she's thinking and
that's that's what how it is with jewish
women we're just
about it like that so and i love that
about myself
you know sometimes i get [__] for being
blatant
and too blunt and maybe i said something
mean to someone
but i'm not gonna apologize for it
because that's who i am
i need to address maybe like if i do
some say something that's insensitive
that's something to address that's
something to look at and learn from and
um analyze but if i'm just
speaking my mind and it's not really
hurting anyone's feelings like
that's just who i am i'm not gonna
apologize for it i think
more people need to learn about
themselves
and i think that'll make everything a
little bit easier because
when you understand yourself you can
understand other people and that's just
what we need more it's more
understanding
absolutely i'm i'm totally with you on
all of those points you
abrielle your perspective is such a gem
um
you're i love working with you i feel
like we have a great friendship along
with our
our work relationship um i mean it just
like we we've all
talked about it you know we're
definitely missing each other we all
work in live events
and so um there's a little bit of
interaction we've done some virtual
stuff but
we're all missing each other so um it
was great to catch up and it was great
to
hear your perspective i appreciate your
perspective
and your friendship um will you go ahead
and
give the people what's going on in your
life um
in in like your social media handles how
can they find you how can they follow
more of you
so i'm really right now i'm just on
instagram
find me abrielle haley a b r i e
l l e h a y l e y one word all lowercase
no special characters
that's really all i am that's all i
that's all i exist in
i try to only exist in that one space i
don't have a lot of social media
i don't post very much on that so if you
really want to get in touch with me send
me a dm
and maybe actually have a conversation
but uh motivational speakers if you uh
yeah motivational speakers i mean that's
the same are you looking to work with
anybody are
you are you in a place of finding new
prospects like
yeah i absolutely am um my email for
that
is elevate me e-l-l-e-b-a-t-e-m-e
gmail.com uh send me an inquiry
anything you wanna work on anything you
wanna do i'm
i am myself in all platforms so i'm just
going to be
if you want to send me a project on my
instagram we can talk there if you want
to send me an email we can talk there
instagram has phone calls now so if you
can you want to facetime me on instagram
whatever you want to do i'm about it
so um cool awesome
yeah well thanks for being here um
reach out people you know like if you if
you want to work together
it's a it's a good good thing that we
have here you know like i i just imagine
you you know in in 10 years like you
continue pursuing all these things that
you're pursuing
continuing your work ethic continually
improving like this guy is the limit for
you
i think that's absolutely the truth
yeah uh listeners i hope you have a good
day
i hope you work out not just to burn
some calories or get in shape for that
vacation coming up i hope that you work
out to feel good to do your best to live
a self-actualized life
i hope that you're drinking water and
not making any excuses for yourself
about this dang water thing
figure out what works for you with your
diet be aware
what's your posture like right now did i
mention drink water
yeah sit up straight stop this hunching
thing that's happening
yeah it's funny i always mention those
like at the beginning in the end of the
podcast because i have a lot of friends
who have told me like dude i'll
you say it and it brings it to my
awareness and all i said i'm like oh
yeah i need to sit up straighter oh i
actually haven't drank any water so
it's all stuff that helps abbrel thanks
again
i appreciate you thank you jake all
right
have a good rest of your day listeners i
still didn't finish
[Music]
knowledge is power